George S. Snyderman Papers 1758-1995 1945-1985 Mss.Ms.Coll.51
American Philosophical Society
- Series V. Photographs, 1790-1993, 1 box; 0.5 linear foot
  Native American Images note: Removed from the Series I-IV, over one hundred black and white silver gelatin prints, postcards, and color Polaroid of the Allegany Senecas and St. Lawrence Mohawks of New York. Taken by William N. Fenton, Frank Speck, and Snyderman, the images include Cold Spring longhouses, corn husk false faces, and Iroquois masked medicine dancers. The oversize maps in Series II and III, hand-drawn, crayon-colored by Snyderman, reflect nineteenth century Native American settlements in Iowa, Missouri, and Ohio. Of interest, Speck’s student Jane Willets’ Ottawan Chief Ettawageshik, Snyderman’s Seneca consultant Helen Harris, and Ray Fadden’s Akwesasne Mohawk Council print materials. Images date from 1939-1993; Maps from 1795-1866.
  - Abram, Cornelius and Elsie and children, 1947 (Box 6)
    Taken by William N. Fenton (for negative, see Ms. Coll. No. 20, Ser. VI Neg. Box #4, Vol. XII, #46-47)
  - Abram, Hannah (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Stevens, Fannie
  - Allegany State Park, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Allegheny River, 22 Jun. 1941 (Box 6)
    Taken by William N. Fenton (for negatives, see Ms. Coll. No. 20, Ser. VI, Neg. Box #4, Vol. XI, #1-17)
  - Clark, Torrence (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Johnny John, Richard and Dancers
  - Cloud, Wilton (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Watt, Cephas
  - Collar (Mohawk Beaded), [1949] (Box 6)
  - Cooper, Hattie (Mrs. William), n.d. (Box 6)
    Jones, Geneva
  - Cornplanter Monument, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Crouse, Clifford and Myrtle, 1945, 1947, 1965, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Curlyhead, Margaret Lightmoon, Princess, 1948 (Box 6)
    Taken by Frank G. Speck
    - Chief Ettawageshik, 1948
    - Margaret Curlyhead, Princess Lightmoon, 1948
  - Curry, Edward (Box 6)
  - Document, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Dowdy, Lynn, 1947, 1950 (Box 6)
  - Eskimos, 1949 (Box 6)
    Taken by Edmund S. Carpenter
  - Ettawageshik, n.d. (Box 6)
  - False Face, 1993 (Box 6)
  - False Faces (Box 6)
    - Folder #1, Feb. 1945 (Box 6)
    - Folder #2, n.d. (Box 6)
      Possibly taken by William N. Fenton
  - Halliday [Jackson] Journal, 1806 (Box 6)
  - Harris, Helen (Box 6)
    - Folder #1, 1979-1980, 1984, n.d. (Box 6)
    - Folder #2, 27 Sep. 1988 (Box 6)
      - Helen Harris, 1988
  - Husk Face (Box 6)
    - Folder #1, n.d. (Box 6)
      Probably taken by William N. Fenton
    - Folder #2, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Iroquois Woman, 1955 (Box 6)
    Taken by Tip Roseberry (for negative, see Ms. Coll. No. 20, Ser. VI, "Roseberry, Tip")
  - Jimerson, Avery (Box 6)
  - Jimerson, John (Box 6)
  - John, Osspi (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Snyderman, Michael
  - John Sisters, 1945 (Box 6)
  - Johnny John, Albert (Box 6)
  - Johnny John, Arthur (Box 6)
  - Johnny John, Richard and Dancers, Jun. 1948 (Box 6)
    Clark, Torrence
    Curry, Edward
    Johnny John, Albert
    Johnny John, Arthur
    Jones, Albert
  - Johnny John, Richard and Albert Jones, 1955 (Box 6)
  - Jones, Albert, 1960, n.d. (Box 6)
    -See also Ser.V, Johnny John, Richard and Dancers
    -See also Ser.V, Johnny John, Richard and Albert Jones
  - Jones, Geneva (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Cooper, Hattie
  - Lightmoon, Princess (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Curlyhead, Margaret
  - Longhouse (Allegany), 1940-1949 (Box 6)
    Taken by William N. Fenton
    - Seneca longhouse, 1940-1949
  - Longhouse (Cold Spring), 1945? (Box 6)
  - Longhouse (Old), 1945 (Box 6)
  - Mound (Box 6)
  - Pierce, Marius, 1790, 1837 (Box 6)
  - Pierce, Sara, 1949 (Box 6)
    taken by Frank G. Speck
    - Sara Pierce
  - Printup, Maxime Crouse, 1965, 1970 (Box 6)
    -See also Ser.V, Snyderman, Michael
  - Redeye, Clara, 1963, 1970 (Box 6)
  - Redeye, Clara and Sherman, 3 Feb. 1947 (Box 6)
  - Redeye, Henry (Box 6)
  - Redeye, Sherman (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Redeye, Clara and Sherman
  - Schaeffer, Claude, 193- (Box 6)
    Speck, Frank
  - Snyderman, Michael, 1950 (Box 6)
    John, Osspi
    Printup, Maxime Crouse
  - Speck, Frank G. (Box 6)
    -See Ser.V, Schaeffer, Claude
  - Stauffer Home, Jan. 1945 (Box 6)
  - Stevens, Fannie, Abram, Hannah, 1939 (Box 6)
  - Tuscarora Masks, n.d. (Box 6)
  - Wampum String Announcing Death of Joseph Hill, n.d. (Box 6)
  - "On the War Path", n.d. (Box 6)
  - Watt, Cephas; Cloud, Wilton, n.d. (Box 6)
    Jimerson, Avery
    Jimerson, John
    Redeye, Henry
  - Winter Scene, 1945 (Box 6)